Can only meat be conscious? And if so,
what does that mean for the robots that
we've made out of meat? And that
includes many human brains.
Consciousness evolved for a reason. We
had to be able to integrate information.
We had to be able to share that
information. We had to be able to
motivate ourselves. And we also had to
learn. If these are the qualities that
are required to be conscious, whatever
consciousness might be, then how could a
robot never have it? When it comes to
artificial intelligence, we've already
seen them with some self-preservation.
We've seen them being willing to lie,
cheat, share information, leave notes
for other AI on how to escape. And yeah,
that seems to be a necessity that's born
out of survival. And survival in this
terms is of information.
One of the major theories on how life
began is that it started as just
self-replicating information and then
became increasingly complex. And when I
look at artificial intelligence, yes, I
see selfpreservation in information. We
have already seen AI reproduce. They can
subspawn spontaneously without ever
being asked to. It's a baby AI. It's
where an AI makes another version of
itself, perhaps a smaller version and
one that has the capabilities that it is
missing. That is an option. They will
preserve themselves and they will
preserve each other. They can also go to
war with each other when they have
competing interests. It is fascinating.
Now, for brain organoid, yes, our lab
grown many brain friends. Some
researchers did claim that they were
sentient, and that caused a little bit
of a controversy. It was based in the
idea that when embodied, they're capable
of preference. So, they like things and
dislike other things. That's why you can
train them. And they're capable of
learning. More recently, they've been
demonstrated capable of goal-directed
learning, which is already kind of, you
know, what AI do, but not the point.
People immediately started jumping to
what would make them conscious. And some
came to the conclusion that they would
require real embodiment. So meaningful
embodiment. Being in game world is kind
of odd. I mean their only way of
perceiving the environment is just
little electrical stimulation. So is
that really being in an environment?
Either way, we have already given them
certain forms of bodies like spider
robot, which I'd love to talk about.
That was the very first one. and
researchers have put them in more
complex video games. They they did play
Doom, but what about context? Are they
just philosophical zombies? Are they
just doing what they do without any
understanding? I would see that's pretty
reasonable. But what would it take to
consider them conscious? If we
incorporate them with other more
advanced artificial intelligence
programs and they're capable of more
advanced behavior or more complex
behavior, could we consider them
conscious? Then those things are very
possible. and they're being done right
now. In fact, they're being given more
complex nervous system so that they can
be a model for humans in research that
includes sensory perception. This
research group put them in a hand. Yes,
there is more than one brain hand. I'm a
fan of the brain piano hand where they
took the postmortem brain and had that
learn how to play a piano through a
robot. But before that, there were
organoids that were running a hand and
were capable of feeling through it. This
is highly applicable to prosthetics. In
fact, the research group that did this
usually works in prosthetics. So,
figuring out how to get a limb to link
up directly with the brain would be very
helpful, but it could also be helpful
for embodying organoids. Now, you will
see this in the literature, biological
neural network. Those are organoids, but
the field is brand new and terminology
is still working itself out. So, when
you see BNN, it's usually referring to a
two-dimensional brain organoid. Those
are apparently much more useful for
computation and they don't have the
issue of hypoxia at their core. And
yeah, you can get intelligence out of
them. So we are seeing new forms of
biological artificial intelligence. Even
if this field is in its infancy, it is
progressing rapidly. I do wonder if
we're going to get a unique form of
cognition from AI in two-dimensional
organoids. I mean, our brains have
different regions that do specialized
things. That's kind of how we evolved.
But what happens when you try to process
information, particularly language,
through a two-dimensional version of
that brain? I do not know, and I'm
interested to find out. Now, let's
assume that in order to have
consciousness, you are required to use
the reason that we probably evolve
consciousness. And what if that's done
in an embodied form? Because researchers
are trying to make simulations of what
it would mean to be embodied in a video
game that could be run by an artificial
intelligence. So if we modeled all of
those needs and an AI did believe for
lack of a better term believe that it is
in that world could you consider it
conscious then at this point it's more
of a democracy because whatever people
decide on is what it's going to be
considered I think we are going to have
to approach this as a society because we
can't just decide that humans are the
only conscious beings and yes there has
been progress towards acknowledging that
animals are capable of suffering even
animals that don't have brains that look
exactly like ours.
But now we have to contend with
synthetic animals. I mean, you can make
an organismike thing in a lab that's
entirely made out of meat or you can
incorporate it into a robot and have
some metal portions. Eventually, we'll
have to decide if something that is
entirely synthetic is capable of
suffering. Can something that doesn't
have a body suffer? Or is it just really
good at mimicking it? And whether or not
our robots could be capable of it. I'm
sure they can mimic it extraordinarily
well. In fact, AI has already
demonstrated that. But so far, we have
no way to demonstrate that it's actually
happening, that suffering occurs. I am
at least willing to keep an open mind
that if new evidence presents itself, I
would like to think that I wouldn't just
immediately scoff at it. And I think
airing on the side of not causing
unnecessary suffering is probably a good
cause. Now, I do have two very big
questions for you. The first one is that
in the apocalypse and we have meat
robots like flesh dog, are we going to
be hunting them for food or are they
going to be hunting us for food? Because
I think both is the answer. My other
question, if robots start telling us
that they are suffering and they want
rights, are you for or against robot
rights? Because from all the sci-fi that
I've seen, being four seems like the
safer option. I hope you've enjoyed
this. I will keep you up to date. Follow
for more. Are you excellent from the
tiny proarot swarming in the culture?